Xavier Guihot

Data Engineer

Penywern Road, SW5 9SX, London, UK Born in 1990

xavierguihot in XavierGuihot

Big data engineer with 3+ years of experience and a background in aeronautics. I am highly proficient at building complex and efficient Scala/Spark data mining pipelines and I love displaying data in a meaningful way specially with d3.js.

SKILLS

Data Mining

Data Visualisation

Advanced

Full Stack Developer

Data Science

Master

spark | scala | etl | hadoop

d3 | python

mongodb | java | sql | javascript | tdd

clustering | hyperparam tuning | bi |

ab testing | sampling

Travel Industry

Advanced

flight search engine

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data engineer at Adthena April 2018- Current

♀ London, (UK) https://www.adthena.com

Adthena is a fast growing start-up and the market leader in Competitive Intelligence for Search. By monitoring millions of search terms on a daily basis, Adthena helps digital marketers understand their paid and organic search landscape and improve campaign performance.

As a data engineer, my role consists in leveraging the massive amount of collected data and serving it to the client facing web application.

- Java backend development: building and maintaining application's endpoints serving SQL data from Amazon Redhsift instances
- Development of Scala/Java Spark pipelines on AWS clusters (Amazon Web Services)

Software developer - Data engineer at Amadeus IT Group October 2014- April 2018

♀ Sophia Antipolis, (FR) http://www.amadeus.com

Amadeus is a global distribution system providing search, pricing, booking, ticketing and other processing services in real-time to travel providers and travel agencies.

I am part of the data mining team in charge of the flight search engine analytics.

- Development of many Scala/Spark pipelines over billions of records on an in-house 30TB-RAM hadoop cluster
- Full stack development of Travel Intelligence visualisation webapps
- Customer choice modeling in order to improve and adapt which flight recommendations are returned, resulting in verified conversion improvements (up to 10%)
- Main role into transitioning workflows and pipelines into Amadeus new Hadoop production cluster (architecture, testing, resiliency, monitoring, git loading container principal reviewer)

Final year internship at Airbus Group April 2014- October 2014

♀ Toulouse Blagnac, (FR) http://www.airbus.com

Airbus is a multinational corporation that designs, manufactures, and sells civil and military aeronautical products worldwide. During my final year internship, as part of the simulation department, I've had the opportunity to develop a workflow editor tool.

First full-stack development experience, getting through each step of the application development cycle

Internship at Karlstad University July 2013- August 2013

TCP simulations with NS2 (network simulator) of large-scale experimental measurements on different cellular networks using different technologies (3G, 4G, TCP variants, ...).

EDUCATION

Engineering School at ISAE SUPAERO

2011 - 2014

♀ Toulouse, (FR)

Major courses: critical computer systems | intelligent systems | aeronautics | mechanical engineering | avionics | fluid mechanics

ISAE: Graduate Institute of Space and Aeronautical Engineering.

French equivalent of a Master's Degree in Engineering.

University at Paris South 11

2009 - 2011

Orsay, (FR)

Major courses: maths | physics | computer science

Two-year university degree in mathematics and physics (DEUG).

Ranked 2 out of 307 in physics and 5 out of 307 in mathematics at the CCP DEUG entrance exam for engineering schools.

LANGUAGES

French Native speaker English Fluent

INTERESTS

Sport

Skills acquired: swimming | cycling | sailing | skiing

Coding

Skills acquired: hackerrank | personal projects

Travel

Skills acquired: youtube